Curriculum Vitae – Martin Bjeldbak Madsen

Personal Information Martin Bjeldbak Madsen June 9th, 1992 (22 years old) Lærkeparken 20 6230 Rødekro Denmark Mobile: +45 26 27 36 60

martin2madsen@gmail.com martinbmadsen.dk

linkedin.com/in/martinbmadsen



I was born and raised in Denmark until I was 5 years of age, whereafter we moved for a total of 9 years abroad, 4 of which were spent in England, and 5 in the US. That means that I'm quite used to speaking Danish and English with locals and can adapt to new cultural environments. Currently I live by myself and in the future, I see myself working in the tech, medicinal, or automotive industries.

Currently I study Computer Science at Aalborg University here in Denmark. I attend 5th semester and engage in interesting problem-based project group work along with following courses. As an example, we as a 6-man group designed and implemented a programming language from the bottom up to make it easier for non-programmers to design board games. This semester is focused on machine intelligence, which piques my interest.

EDUCATION

I have quite a normal educational background, except for the physical locations! Educational-wise, I plan to take the first year of my 2-year master's in the US and then finish it at Aalborg University.

Aalborg University - Bachelor of Science, Computer Sience (2011 - 2014) Bachelor's degree in Computer Science (180 ECTS credits). I graduated with an average of B on the European ECTS scale. My master's degree will be completed during the summer of 2016.

EUC Nord - HTX (2008 - 2011) Technical gymnasium in Hjørring, Denmark. Finished the Higher Technical Examination Programme (HTX), a 3-year vocationally oriented general upper secondary programme, and a prerequisite for admission to higher education. I took the highest level Math, Physics, English, and Danish possible.

Bagterpskolen (2006 - 2008) Completed the Danish Folkeskole Education in Hjørring, Denmark.

J. R. Gerrits Middle School (2003 - 2006) Elementary and Middle School i Kimberly, Wisconsin, USA.

Professional experience

September 2012 → now Student programmer at Falck Healthcare a/s. I develop and maintain a web portal used by Falck's physiotherapists when journaling their contact with patients. I spend around 15 hours per week working there alongside my studies.

Sept 2010 → January 2014 Ran my own company, *Divambu*. I developed and hosted web sites for small companies.

October 2008 → June 2010 Service worker at Fakta a/s (part of Coop Denmark). Was in direct contact with customers and fulfilled everyday tasks required to run a busy grocery store. I worked during evenings, weekends, and holidays alongside attending school full-time while I was under 18.

OTHER ACTIVITY

July 2012 → March 2014 Mentor, Project Solskinsunge 2012. Volenteer work, where we arrange bi-monthly social gatherings for teenagers aged 15 – 18, most of which are second generation immigrants.

Furthermore, I was responsible for contacting organizations and companies to gather sponsorships for a software development camp hosted by UNF, The Danish Youth Association of Science in the summer of 2013. During the week-long camp itself, I helped the mostly young participants with any problems they might have had when developing their Android applications.

In January 2013, I was elected to sit on the Study Board for Computer Science at Aalborg University (link). Here we take on responsibilities for bachelor and master programs within the following educations Computer Science, Informatics, Information Technology, Software Engineering, and Software Construction and their curricular. Here we receive and discuss, among others, qualification and exemption applications, quality assurance of the above educations.

I've had a Danish driver's license for 3 years.

SKILLS

I can quickly involve myself in new material, but there are a few technologies and systems I have more experience with than others:

Operating systems Basic understanding of most Unix-like systems: Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, Arch Linux, Mac OS X.

Servers and databases Nginx.

CMS-systems I've set up systems with Wordpress, phpBB, Octopress.

Revision control Git, SVN.

Programming, scripting, and markup languages Land XaTeX, HTML, CSS, C, C‡, Java, JavaScript and jQuery, Ruby and Ruby on Rails.

Language

My native language is Danish, but almost everything I write and read is in English, both academically at university and merely communicating to others when I'm at home, coding or not.

Danish first language Spoken English fluent Written English fluent

Interests

When I'm not in front of my computer, I love to enjoy a cup of tea and read non-fiction. There is also nothing better than travelling the world, so I try to do that as much as possible, and thankfully due to my fantastic friends, I've had quite a few fantastic experiences travelling to visit then. I also enjoy electronic and classical music, such as house and Tchaikovsky. Keeping my body healthy and in shape is also important to me, so naturally I quite enjoy cooking sexy, irresistable food!